Guide to the Millicent Todd Bingham Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Personal Papers, 1874-1968; Series VIII; 10 linear feet (23 boxes)
  - Persons
    - Richardson, George L.: article about John A. Wilder (Box 165, Folder 215)
    - Roberts, Walter Orr (Box 165, Folder 216)
    - Rogers, Henry M. (Box 165, Folder 217)
    - Salter, Katherine Hayden (Box 165, Folder 218)
    - Sawyer, Elizabeth C. (Box 165, Folder 219)
    - Sewall, Richard B. (Box 165, Folder 220)
    - Smidt, Kristian (Box 165, Folder 221)
    - Stearns, Foster (Box 165, Folder 222)
    - ________, Martha Genung (Box 165, Folder 222)
    - ________, Mary Kittredge (Box 165, Folder 222)
    - Swärd, Sune (Box 165, Folder 223)
    - Sweeney, Catherine H. (Box 165, Folder 224)
    - Thomas, Joe C. (Box 165, Folder 225)
    - Thompson, Daniel V. (Box 166, Folder 226)
    - Thompson, William L. (Box 166, Folder 227)
    - Thoreau, Henry David
      - "The Thoreau Family Two Generations Ago," by Mabel Loomis Todd (Box 166, Folder 228)
      - Millicent Todd Bingham's notes and lists (Box 166, Folder 229)
      - Articles about Thoreau, 1881-1904, 1950-1968 (Box 166, Folder 230-231)
      - Thoreau Society Bulletin, 1950-1968 (Box 166, Folder 232-233)
      - Thoreau Society booklets, 1954-1964 (Box 166, Folder 234-236)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 166, Folder 237)
      - Printed matter (Box 166, Folder 238)
    - Todd, David Peck
      - Biographical articles and obituaries, 1925-1940 (Box 166, Folder 239)
      - Correspondence, 1882-1934 (Box 167, Folder 240)
      - Copies of correspondence and articles about David Peck Todd (Box 167, Folder 241-242)
      - Newspaper clippings (Box 167, Folder 243)
      - Notes, printed matter (Box 167, Folder 244)
      - Correspondence and notes concerning death of David Peck Todd, 1939 May-August (Box 167, Folder 245)
      - Diary by Millicent Todd Bingham concerning death of David Peck Todd, 1939 July (Box 167, Folder 246)
      - Correspondence about David Peck Todd biography, 1939-1966 (Box 167, Folder 247)
    - Todd, James M. (Box 167, Folder 248)
    - Todd, Mabel (Loomis)
      - Reminiscences (Box 167, Folder 249)
      - Notes, newspaper clippings (Box 167, Folder 250)
      - Booklet made for her by Millicent Todd, 1912 (Box 167, Folder 251)
    - Waite, Frederick C. (Box 167, Folder 252)
    - Wambaugh, Sarah (Box 167, Folder 253)
    - ________, Eugene (Box 167, Folder 253)
    - Ward, Robert De Courey (Box 167, Folder 254)
    - Wheelwright, Mary C. (Box 167, Folder 255)
    - Whitman, Walt (Box 167, Folder 256)
    - Wickersham, George W. (Box 167, Folder 257)
    - Wilbur, Richard (Box 167, Folder 258)
    - Wilcox, Walter F. (Box 167, Folder 259)
    - Wilder, Charles T. (Box 167, Folder 260)
    - Wilder, Elizabeth Johnston (Box 167, Folder 261)
    - Wilder, John A. (Box 167, Folder 262)
    - Williams, Talcott (Box 167, Folder 263)
    - Wright, Louise W. (Box 167, Folder 264)
    - Zahn, Bernard (Box 167, Folder 265)
    - Zahniser, Howard (Box 167, Folder 266)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 167, Folder 267)
  - Clubs and Organizations
    - America First Committee (Box 168, Folder 268)
    - American Geographical Society (Box 168, Folder 269)
    - American Museum of Natural History (Box 168, Folder 270)
    - American Ornithologists Union (Box 168, Folder 271)
    - American Pen Women, Miami Branch (Box 168, Folder 272)
    - American Psychological Association (Box 168, Folder 273)
    - Amherst Bicentennial Committee (Box 168, Folder 274)
    - Amherst College (Box 168, Folder 275-276)
    - Amherst Historical Society (Box 168, Folder 278)
    - Beloit College (Box 168, Folder 279)
    - Carnegie Institution of Washington (Box 168, Folder 280)
    - Carnegie-Mellon University, Pittsburgh (Box 168, Folder 281)
    - College Club of Pittsburgh (Box 168, Folder 282)
    - Community Chest (Box 168, Folder 283)
    - Convent Alumnae Association [Mrs. Stearns School] (Box 168, Folder 284-285)
    - Cosmopolitan Club (Box 168, Folder 286)
    - Council for the Promotion of Field Studies (Box 168, Folder 287)
    - Daughters of the American Revolution, Mary Mattoon Chapter (Box 169, Folder 288-289)
    - Daughters of the American Revolution, National Society (Box 169, Folder 290)
    - Dickinson College (Box 169, Folder 291)
    - Florida Civil War Centennial Commission (Box 169, Folder 292)
    - Folger Library (Box 169, Folder 293)
    - Goodspeed's Book Shop (Box 169, Folder 294)
    - The Grolier Club (Box 169, Folder 295)
    - Guggenheim, John Simon, Memorial Foundation (Box 169, Folder 296)
    - Historical Association of Southern Florida (Box 169, Folder 297-298)
    - Institut des Sciences de l'Education (Box 169, Folder 299)
    - International Congress of Psychology (Box 169, Folder 300-301)
    - International Congress of Psychology (Box 170, Folder 302)
    - International Institute of Intellectual Cooperation (Box 170, Folder 303)
    - Ipswich, Mass., Chamber of Commerce (Box 170, Folder 304)
    - Jones Library, Amherst, Mass. (Box 170, Folder 305)
    - Journey's End, Boxford, Mass. (Box 170, Folder 306)
    - Laymen's Movement (Box 170, Folder 307)
    - League of Nations Union (Box 170, Folder 308)
    - League of Women Voters (Box 170, Folder 309)
    - Libraire Saint-François (Box 170, Folder 310)
    - Library of Congress (Box 170, Folder 311)
    - Lincoln County Memorial Hospital (Box 170, Folder 312)
    - Literary Society of Washington, D.C. (Box 170, Folder 313-317)
    - Maine Federation of Women's Clubs (Box 171, Folder 318)
    - Massachusetts, University of (Box 171, Folder 319)
    - Mount Holyoke College (Box 171, Folder 320)
    - Nassau Community College (Box 171, Folder 321)
    - National Archives (Box 171, Folder 322)
    - National Audubon Society (Box 171, Folder 323)
    - National Geographic Society (Box 171, Folder 324)
    - National Portrait Gallery, Smithsonian Institution (Box 171, Folder 325)
    - Pan-American League (Box 171, Folder 326-327)
    - The Patriotic Club, Bremen, Maine (Box 171, Folder 328)
    - Personnel Research Federation (Box 171, Folder 329)
    - Pittsburgh Bibliophiles (Box 171, Folder 330)
    - Radcliffe College (Box 171, Folder 331)
    - Radcliffe Club (Box 171, Folder 332)
    - Red Cross (Box 171, Folder 333)
    - Serbian Agricultural Relief Committee of America (Box 171, Folder 334)
    - Smithsonian Institution (Box 171, Folder 335)
    - Traveler's Club, Amherst, Mass. (Box 171, Folder 336)
    - Vassar College (Box 171, Folder 337)
    - Vassar College (Box 172, Folder 338-344)
    - Wellesley College (Box 172, Folder 345)
    - Westinghouse Talent Search (Box 172, Folder 346-348)
    - Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation (Box 172, Folder 349)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 172, Folder 350)
  - Subject Files
    - Travel notes and memorabilia
      - Europe, 1899 (Box 173, Folder 351)
      - North Africa and Southeast Asia, 1901 (Box 173, Folder 352)
      - Tripoli, 1905 (Box 173, Folder 353)
      - Paris, 1905-1906 (Box 173, Folder 354)
      - South America, 1907 (Box 173, Folder 355-356)
      - Berlin, 1909-1910 (Box 173, Folder 357)
      - Russia, 1914 (Box 173, Folder 358)
      - Southern Florida, 1920-1930 (Box 173, Folder 359)
      - Ireland, 1934 (Box 173, Folder 360)
      - England and Scandinavia, 1951 (Box 173, Folder 361)
      - Florida, 1965 (Box 173, Folder 362)
      - Miscellaneous, 1896-1949 (Box 173, Folder 363)
    - World War I
      - MTB notes and financial records (Box 173, Folder 364)
      - Official papers (Box 173, Folder 365)
      - Writings and drawings by others (Box 173, Folder 366)
      - Printed matter (Box 173, Folder 367-368)
    - Todd-Bingham Papers
      - Correspondence with Library of Congress and MTB notes, 1947-1963 (Box 173, Folder 369)
      - Correspondence with Yale University Library
        - 1946-1960 1946-1960 (Box 173, Folder 370)
        - 1961-1968 1961-1968 (Box 174, Folder 371-378)
      - Legal agreements with Yale University Library (Box 174, Folder 379)
      - Acknowledgements of gifts to Yale University Library (Box 174, Folder 380)
      - Lists of material donated to Yale University Library (Box 174, Folder 381)
      - Correspondence with Gladys MacKenzie, 1957-1968 August (Box 174, Folder 382-392)
      - Correspondence with Gladys MacKenzie, 1968 September-December (Box 175, Folder 393)
      - Correspondence with Elizabeth Lawrence and MTB notes, 1964-1968 (Box 175, Folder 394)
      - Correspondence with Peabody Museum, 1964-1966 (Box 175, Folder 395-397)
      - Lists of materials donated to Peabody Museum (Box 175, Folder 398)
      - Correspondence and notes concerning collection of South American butterflies (Box 175, Folder 399)
      - Correspondence with other Yale departments and lists of donations (Box 175, Folder 400)
    - Planetarium, efforts to build in Washington, D.C., 1965 (Box 175, Folder 401)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts
      - Drawings (Box 175, Folder 402)
      - Poems (Box 175, Folder 403)
      - Articles by others (Box 175, Folder 404)
      - Writings by others (Box 175, Folder 405)
    - Printed Matter
      - Calling cards and greeting cards (Box 175, Folder 406)
      - Invitations (Box 175, Folder 407)
      - Programs of concerts, meetings and plays (Box 175, Folder 408)
      - Programs of concerts, meetings and plays (Box 176, Folder 409)
      - Paperbound book by Arlo Bates (Box 176, Folder 410)
      - Religious cards, leaflets and broadsides (Box 176, Folder 411)
      - Flowers and horticulture (Box 176, Folder 412)
      - Art (Box 176, Folder 413)
      - Music (Box 176, Folder 414)
      - Maps (Box 176, Folder 415-416)
      - Recipes (Box 176, Folder 417)
      - Ship passenger lists (Box 176, Folder 418)
      - Newspapers, 1874 (Box 176, Folder 419)
      - Commercial and advertisement items (Box 176, Folder 420)
      - Broadsides and miscellaneous items (Box 177, Folder 421)
      - Booklets and articles (Box 177, Folder 422)
      - Pamphlets (Box 177, Folder 423-424)
- Legal and Financial, 1883-1969; Series IX; 6 linear feet (14 boxes)
  Correspondence and Bills and Receipts are arranged chronologically. All other sections are organized by subject and form of material.
  - Correspondence
    - 1896-1937 Jun (Box 178, Folder 1-19)
    - 1937 Jul-1942 May (Box 179, Folder 20-35)
    - 1942 Jun-1949 (Box 180, Folder 36-45)
    - 1950-1959 (Box 181, Folder 46-57)
    - 1960-1968, no date (Box 182, Folder 58-66)
  - Legal Papers
    - Passports, 1905-1957 (Box 183, Folder 67)
    - 1922-1966 (Box 183, Folder 68)
    - Wills
      - 1927-1967 (Box 183, Folder 69-77)
      - Reference material (Box 183, Folder 78)
    - Funeral arrangements (Box 183, Folder 79)
    - Estate of David Peck Todd
      - Correspondence, 1912-1939 (Box 183, Folder 80)
      - Papers, 1914-1940 (Box 183, Folder 81)
      - Bank statements, 1938-1939 (Box 184, Folder 82)
      - Check books, 1883-1940 (Box 184, Folder 83)
      - Illness, 1925-1939 (Box 184, Folder 84)
    - Estate of Mabel Loomis Todd, 1898-1941 (Box 184, Folder 85)
    - Estate of Walter VanDyke Bingham, 1952-1964 (Box 184, Folder 86)
    - Arthur Curtiss James Trust, 1925-1956 (Box 184, Folder 87)
  - Property and Real Estate
    - Hotel register, Paint Breeze, 1908-1919 (Box 184, Folder 88)
    - Leases (Box 184, Folder 89)
    - Mortgages and sales agreements
      - 1909-1924 (Box 184, Folder 90)
      - Advertisements, 1936-1947 (Box 185, Folder 91)
    - Taxes, 1931-1965 (Box 185, Folder 92-94)
    - Rental receipts, 1943-1961 (Box 185, Folder 95)
    - Insurance, 1927-1966 (Box 185, Folder 96-97)
    - Life insurance, 1909-1947 (Box 185, Folder 98)
    - Theft of property at 110 Washington Place, 1937 September 2 (Box 185, Folder 99)
    - Inventories
      - 1920-1939 (Box 185, Folder 100-101)
      - 1940-1968 (Box 186, Folder 102)
      - Books (Box 186, Folder 103)
    - Gifts
      - Library of Congress, 1943-1967 (Box 186, Folder 104)
      - 1961-1964 (Box 186, Folder 105)
    - Maintenance and storage, 1915-1969, undated (Box 186, Folder 106-110)
    - Architectural drawings (Box 187, Folder 111)
    - Maps of Washington Square (Box 187, Folder 112)
    - Maps of Florida (Box 187, Folder 113)
  - Stocks
    - Certificates: Walter VanDyke Bingham (WVB), 1932 (Box 187, Folder 114)
    - Statements: Millicent Todd Bingham (MTB), 1930-1966 (Box 187, Folder 115-118)
    - Statements: WVB, 1939-1946 (Box 187, Folder 119)
    - Summaries and notes
      - Millicent Todd Bingham, 1917-1966 (Box 187, Folder 120)
      - Walter VanDyke Bingham, 1925-1952 (Box 187, Folder 121)
    - Stock transaction receipts
      - Millicent Todd Bingham, 1917-1966 (Box 187, Folder 122)
      - Millicent Todd Bingham and Walter VanDyke Bingham, 1940-1966 (Box 187, Folder 123-124)
  - Taxes
    - Federal income tax
      - Millicent Todd Bingham and Walter VanDyke Bingham, 1940-1952 (Box 188, Folder 125)
      - Millicent Todd Bingham, 1917-1966 (Box 188, Folder 126-132)
      - Walter VanDyke Bingham, 1918-1953 (Box 188, Folder 133-135)
    - Massachusetts income tax: MTB, 1918-1919 (Box 188, Folder 136)
    - New York State income tax: MTB and WVB, 1925-1941 (Box 188, Folder 137)
    - District of Columbia income tax
      - Millicent Todd Bingham and Walter VanDyke Bingham, 1941 (Box 188, Folder 138)
      - Millicent Todd Bingham, 1935-1965 (Box 188, Folder 139)
      - Walter VanDyke Bingham, 1940-1952 (Box 189, Folder 140)
    - District of Columbia property tax: WVB, 1950-1953 (Box 189, Folder 141)
  - Bills and Receipts
    - 1899-1949 (Box 189, Folder 142-146)
    - 1940-1968, no date (Box 190, Folder 147-152)
    - Royalty statements
      - Millicent Todd Bingham, Walter VanDyke Bingham, and David Peck Todd, 1915-1928 (Box 190, Folder 153)
      - Millicent Todd Bingham and Walter VanDyke Bingham, 1930-1967 (Box 191, Folder 154-157)
- Walter Vandyke Bingham Papers, 1883-1962; Series X; 2 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series is organized by form of material (e.g., writings), and by subject (e.g., war service). Within each category, items are arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence, 1907-1956, undated (Box 192, Folder 1-4)
  - Correspondence with John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1937 (Box 192, Folder 5)
  - Biographical material
    - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, correspondence, notes and articles about WVB, 1929-1954 (Box 192, Folder 6-7)
    - Notes, articles and letters by and about WVB, 1897-1953 (Box 192, Folder 8)
    - Clippings (Box 192, Folder 9)
  - Writings
    - "Studies in Melody", 1910 January (Box 192, Folder 10)
    - Drafts of "Personality and Vocation - A Note on Effects of Introversion on Dominant Interests", 1926 (Box 192, Folder 11)
    - Pamphlets and articles, 1933-1947, undated (Box 192, Folder 12)
    - From A History of Psychology in Autobiography, 1952 (Box 192, Folder 13)
    - "Personnel Utilization - Classification and Assignment of Military Personnel... During WW II", 1952 May 21 (Box 192, Folder 14)
    - "Collected Papers"
      - 1907-1924 (Box 193, Folder 15-16)
      - 1925-1938 (Box 194, Folder 17-18)
      - 1939-1954 (Box 195, Folder 19-20)
    - Notes on Pittsburgh industries, undated (Box 196, Folder 21)
    - Notes, 1925-1951, undated (Box 196, Folder 22-24)
    - Bibliography, 1962 (Box 196, Folder 24a)
  - Memoranda books, 1950-1952, undated (Box 196, Folder 25)
  - War service material, 1941-1945 (Box 196, Folder 26)
  - Ration books, 1942-1945 (Box 196, Folder 27)
  - Financial records, 1912-1951 (Box 196, Folder 28-29)
  - Clippings, 1883-1953, undated (Box 196, Folder 30)
  - Printed matter, 1899-1953, undated (Box 196, Folder 31-32)
  - Memorabilia, undated (Box 196, Folder 33)
- Additions, 1981 October 19
  - Leyda, Jay (Box 200)
    General note
    Catalogue of poems and letters by Emily Dickinson filmed at the Folger Shakespeare Library, Washington, D.C. 1957. It lists the poems and letters with their assigned numbers in the order in which they appear on the film. For the Yale copy of the film, see MICROFILM 911.
- Books about Emily Dickinson, 1902-1957; Series XI; 1 linear foot (3 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by author.
  - Inscriptions to Millicent Todd Bingham in presentation copies of Emily Dickinson books (Box 197)
  - Martha Dickinson Bianchi (Box 197)
    - Emi1y Dickinson Face to Face, 1932 (Box 197)
    - The Life and Letters of Emily Dickinson, 1924 (Box 197)
  - Martha Dickinson Bianchi and Arthur Leete Hampson
    - Further Poems of Emily Dickinson, 1929 (Box 197)
    - The Poems of Emily Dickinson, 1930 (Box 197)
    - Unpublished Poems of Emily Dickinson, 1935 1935 (Box 197)
  - Millicent Todd Bingham
    - Emily Dickinson's Home, 1955 1955 (Box 197)
    - Emily Dickinson - A Revelation (2 copies), 1954 (Box 198)
    - Eighteen Poems by Emily Dickinson, 1957 (Box 198)
  - MacGregor Jenkins, 1930 (Box 198)
  - Thomas H. Johnson
    - Emily Dickinson, An Interpretive Biography, 1955 (Box 198)
    - The Poems of Emily Dickinson (3 volumes), 1955 (Box 198)
  - Mabel Loomis Todd
    - Letters of Emily Dickinson, 1931 1931 (Box 198)
    - Letters of Emily Dickinson (second copy), 1931 (Box 199)
    - Letters of Emily Dickinson, 1951 1951 (Box 199)
    - Poems by Emily Dickinson, Third Series, 1917 (Box 199)
    - Letters of Emily Dickinson, 1845-1886, 1906 (Box 199)
  - Mabel Loomis Todd and Thomas Wentworth Higginson, Poems by Emily Dickinson, 1902 (Box 199)
  - Mabel Loomis Todd and Millicent Todd Bingham, Bolts of Melody, 1945 (Box 199)
  - Alma G. Watson, "Guests in Eden", 1946 (Box 199)
  - George Frisbie Whicher, This Was a Poet, 1938 (Box 199)